musingsofamuse.com 2019-06-28

# Privacy Policy – Musings of a Muse

Updated: May 25th, 2018 

### Please read the terms of use carefully and if you do not agree to these terms please do not access this site.

In this Web Site Privacy Statement (“statement”), we, musingsofamuse.com provide information about how we collect, use and transfer personally identifiable data from you, a web site visitor, through www.musingsofamuse.com, and other web sites that we operate and on which we post a direct link to this statement (collectively the “site”).

### Scope.

This statement covers only data collected through the site and not any other data collection or processing, including, without limitation, data collection practices of other web pages to which we link or data that we or our affiliates collect offline or through web sites that do not display a direct link to this statement.

### Types of Data and Collection Methods.

When you visit the site, we automatically receive and record information from your computer and Internet connection, such as the IP address of your computer and/or Internet service provider, the date and time you access our web sites, the Internet address of web sites from which you link to our site, the computer technology you are using and your movements and preferences on our site. We use technology that many other web sites employ, including, without limitation, “cookies” or small data files stored on your computer’s hard drive, to collect information such as the aforementioned. In some instances, we also use cookies to collect information in connection with future visits from that site, to recognize you as a previous visitor and to track your activity on our site. You do not need to have cookies turned on to participate in our surveys or to visit our site. You can refuse cookies by turning them off on your browser at any time. 

To the extent permitted by applicable law, we reserve the right to combine the various types of data that we collect.

### Collection Purposes, Use of Data.

We use the data we collect for the following general purposes (we do not share your information with anyone else nor is it sold):

  *   * To respond to the request that you sent us such as your request for information, or your request to subscribe to a service we offer;
  * To administer, protect and improve our site and our systems;
  * To better understand the preferences of our site visitors;
  * To identify server problems;
  * To compile aggregated statistics about site usage;
  * To help personalize your experience of our site;
  * To improve our products and services and other internal business purposes; and
  * To inform you about our products and services.

### We do not share your information with anyone but this site does use third-party services as well as ad networks and affiliates.

Below is personal data collected for the following services and the data they collect:  
**Akismet Anti-Spam** a plugin that helps to prevent comment spam. They may use IP information to flag comments which they believe to be spam. Please see their privacy policy to see how IP data is use.  
**Madmimi** a service we utilize that delivers updates daily via e-mail in the form of a newsletter. Sign up is optional and never automated. Madmimi may store e-mail addresses in order to deliver the daily newsletter please see their privacy policy to see how e-mail addresses are used.  
**Cloudflare** a service used to for website security as well as to deliver users a fast, speedy experience while browsing the site. Please see their privacy policy should you have concerns about data they might collect.  
**Google Analytics** a service used to track stats on this website. Cookie and usage data is collected by Google and their privacy policy can be found here regarding that usage.  
Interaction with external social networks and platforms such as Intagram, Facebook, Pinterest, etc…which may collect data usage and IP addresses please the privacy statements for further information.  
**Statcounter** a service used to track stats on this website. Cookie and usage data is collected via this service and their privacy policy can be access by clicking here.  
**Gravity Forms Plugin** which is used to contact the editor of this site. This plugin has access to your e-mail address when messages are sent please refer to their privacy policy for more information. 

Please feel free to contact us with any comments, questions, complaints or suggestions you might have regarding the information practices described in this statement. You may send us email [here](https://www.musingsofamuse.com/contact "Contact Us!").
